hey everyone Merry Christmas and we're
嘿，大家圣诞快乐，我们要谈论的是一棵长大的树
gonna be talking about a tree that grows
our crypto currency like Bitcoin and
我们的加密货币，例如比特币和，它被称为默克尔树
eternium and it's called a Merkel tree
what is a Merkel tree the best way to
默克尔树是什么，解释当地树的最好方法是展示
explain what a local tree is is to show
you how to build one and to construct a
您如何构建一个树并构建Merkle树，首先要从一个树开始
Merkle tree you first start with a
non-empty array for simplicity we're
非空数组为简单起见，我们将假设
going to assume that the length of the
array is a power of two for example the
数组是2的幂，例如，数组的长度可以是2 4 8 16 32
length of the array can be 2 4 8 16 32
but it can't be 6 since 6 is not a power
但是它不可能是6，因为6不是2的幂
of 2 you'll see in a moment why we're
gonna need an array with a length of
每个元素中的下一个元素将需要一个幂为2的数组
power 2 next for each element in the
array we're gonna compute the
数组，我们将计算元素的密码哈希，
cryptographic hash of the element and
then store it in a new array from this
然后将其存储在孵化场阵列中的新阵列中，我们采用第一个
array of hatcheries we take the first
element and then compute the hash we
元素，然后计算哈希，我们取下两个元素，然后
take the next two elements and then
compute the hash and we continue this
计算散列，然后继续此过程，直到计算出的散列
process until we computed the hash of
the last two elements next we take this
接下来的最后两个元素我们采用此计算的哈希并重复整个
computed hashes and repeat the whole
process eventually you'll get a single
最后，您将获得一个哈希，这称为根哈希，
hash and this is called a root hash and
this is how you construct the Merkle
如果元素中的数量众多，这就是您现在构造Merkle树的方式
tree now if the number of elements in
the original array is not a pal - then
原始数组不是好朋友-然后在本地树的某个点
at some point of the local tree
construction there will be an odd number
构造，例如，如果您计算的哈希数将是奇数
of computed hashes for example if you
start out with 6 elements then you'll
从6个元素开始，然后在计算
get 3 hashes after computing the hash of
the pair's
这对的，就像你从这里看到的那样，我们不能
and as you can see from here we cannot
compute the next level of hashes since
计算哈希的下一个级别，因为我们需要4个哈希，但是只有3个
we need 4 hashes but there's only three
here so if there are odd number of
因此，如果散列数量奇数，那么计算
hashes then the trick to compute the
next level of hashes is to duplicate the
哈希的下一个级别是复制最后一个元素，然后计算哈希
last element and then compute the hash
of the duplicates in essence this is
从本质上讲，这些重复项就像填充数组的尾端一样
like filling the tail end of the array
with duplicates so that the length of
与重复项，以便数组的长度变得明显-那么如何
the array becomes apparent - so how is a
more culturally useful one application
默克尔树在文化上更有用的一种应用是
of the Merkel tree is that you
and create a cryptographic proof that a
并创建加密证明，证明交易包含在区块中
transaction was included in a block
imagine that there are a bunch of
想象有很多交易正在等待
transactions that are waiting to be
included in a block to create your
包含在一个块中以创建您的密码证明，以证明这些未决
cryptographic proof that these pending
transactions are included in the next
交易包含在下一个区块中，我们首先构建镶嵌
block we first construct the marquetry
from these transactions and we include
从这些交易中，我们现在将默克尔根哈希值包含在块中
the merkel root hash into the block now
if Alice wants to know if her
爱丽丝是否想知道她的交易是否包含在该区块中
transaction was included in the block
all she has to do is get these four
她要做的就是得到这四个哈希，我们计算默克尔根哈希
hashes we compute the Merkel root hash
and then compared with the mercury ash
然后将其与书中承诺的汞灰进行比较
that was committed to the book if the
two merkel root hash is are equal then
两个默克尔根哈希值相等，那么她知道我们的交易是
she knows that our transaction was
included in the block now another way to
现在包含在该区块中的另一种创建交易证明的方式
create a proof that a transaction was
included in a block is to concatenate
包含在一个块中的是连接所有交易数据并创建一个
all of the transaction data and create a
single hash from it the problem with
从它的单个散列这种方法的问题是，为了
this approach is that in order to
recompute the hash you need all the
重新计算散列，您需要所有交易数据，所以如果有1,000
transaction data so if there was 1,000
transactions in a block and if Alice
交易是否完整，爱丽丝是否想知道她的交易是否
wants to know if her transaction was
included in the block then she will have
包括在区块中，那么她将必须下载所有1,000笔交易，并且
to download all 1,000 transactions and
then compute the hash however using the
然后计算散列值，但是使用镶嵌，她只需要记录两个
marquetry she only needs log two of
1,000 which is about ten ashes
1,000，大约是十个骨灰，因此在摘要中创建的Oracle三重奏
so in summary Oracle trios you to create
a small cryptographic proof that a
证明一组数据中包含某些数据的小型密码证明
certain data is included in a set of
data and using this property you can
数据并使用此属性，您可以创建证明交易是
create a proof that a transaction was
included in a block next let's implement
接下来，让我们实现一个功能，该功能将验证本地
a function that will verify a local
proof in solidity we'll name the
坚实的证明，我们将函数命名为verify，它将采用
function verify and it's gonna taking
four inputs an array of hashes that I
四个输入散列数组，我需要这些散列来计算maca根
needed to compute the maca root the
mercury itself the hash of the element
汞本身用于构造数组的元素的哈希
in the array that was used to construct
the marquetry
镶嵌和数组中的索引，其中
and the index in the array where the
element is stored this function will
元素被存储，如果可以重新创建该函数，则该函数将返回true。
return true if it can recreate the
mercury from the proof leaf and index
证明叶子和索引中的汞，否则它将返回
otherwise it will return
Falls we all start with the leaf
瀑布我们都从叶子重新计算美国规则开始，然后进行比较
recompute America rule and then compare
with tomorrow rule that was provided to
用明天的规则来建立我们的Marco规则，我们需要四个循环
build our Marco rule we need a four loop
that will update the hash with elements
首先使用证明的元素更新哈希
of the proof first let's try to figure
out how to compute the parent hash from
找出如何从Merkle树的最底部计算父哈希
the very bottom of the Merkle tree
notice that the indexes of the left
请注意，左叶的索引全部为偶数，而左叶的索引为
leaves are all even and indexes of the
right leaves are all odd so this means
右边的叶子都是奇数，所以这意味着如果索引是偶数，那么我们需要
that if the index is even then we need
to append the proof element to our
将证明元素附加到我们的客户哈希中，然后更新哈希
client hash and then update the hash
otherwise the index is odd which means
否则索引为奇数，这意味着我们的哈希属于正确的
that our hash belongs to the right
branch and we need to pretend our proof
分支，我们需要在更新哈希和
element before updating the hash and
this will give us the hash one double
这将使我们从哈希表的最底部开始将哈希值提高一倍
above from the very bottom of the
marquetry we want to repeat this logic
镶嵌，我们想在连接当前哈希值的地方重复此逻辑
where we concatenate our current hash
with the proof element if the current
带有证明元素，如果当前哈希属于左分支，并且
hash belongs to the left branch and if
our crane has belongs to the right
我们的起重机属于正确的分支，那么我们想将我们的起重机连接起来
branch then we want to concatenate our
proof element with the hash and then
带有散列的证明元素，然后更新散列，现在请注意，如果我们
update the hash now notice that if our
starting index is t then our pan index
起始索引是t，那么我们的全景索引是1，如果起始索引是2，那么
is 1 and if our starting index is 2 then
I pan index is also 1 and in general if
I pan索引也为1，通常，如果我们的索引为2k或2k加1，则
our index is either 2k or 2k plus 1 then
our parent index is equal to K in other
我们的父索引等于K，换句话说，我们将客户索引除以2
words we divide our client index by 2
and round down to the nearest integer
并四舍五入到最接近的整数以及您的处理方式，因此D为
and the way you do it in so the D is
like this and this completes the code to
像这样，这样就完成了验证我们的默克尔证明的代码，现在开始
verify our merkel proof now let's go
over how this function would work let's
关于此功能的工作原理，我们假设有8个元素，
say that there are 8 elements and we
want to verify that the third element is
要验证此Merkle树中是否包含第三个元素，因此
contained in this Merkle tree so the
proof must be an array of hash of the
证明必须是第四个元素的哈希数组，哈希的哈希值
fourth element the hash of the hashes of
the first and second element and the
第一个和第二个元素以及从右侧计算出的哈希
hash computed from the right side of the
marquetry
镶嵌，叶子将是第三个散列
the leaf will be the hash of the third
element
元素和索引将是两个，我们从
and the index will be two we start from
the hash of the third element
第三个元素的哈希值，因为索引等于我们的证明
since the index is equal to our proof
element must come from the right so we
元素必须来自右侧，因此我们将散列与的散列连接在一起
concatenate our hash with the hash of
the fourth element and then update our
第四个元素，然后更新我们的哈希，然后更新我们的索引我们的索引
hash and then update our index our index
was two before so two divided by two is
在之前是二，所以二除以二等于一，犯罪指数现在是
equal to one and crime index is now
equal to one and we move on to the next
等于1，我们继续进行for循环的下一个迭代
iteration of the for loop since our
current index is equal to one this means
当前索引等于1，这意味着我们的证明元素必须位于
that our proof element must be on the
left side so we append occurring hash to
左侧，因此我们将出现的哈希值附加到第二个证明元素，然后更新
the second proof element and then update
the hash and then update the index the
哈希，然后更新索引，索引等于1，所以1除以2是
index is equal to 1 so 1 divided by 2 is
0.5 but since we're doing integer
0.5，但由于我们要进行整数除法，因此四舍五入到最接近的值
division we round down to the nearest
integer and the 0.5 round the town will
整数，城镇的0.5舍入将为0，因此我们的索引现在等于0且
be 0 so our index is now equal to 0 and
that completes the second iteration for
这样就完成了第二次迭代，第三次也是最后一次迭代索引
the third and final iteration the index
is now equal to 0 so the proof element
现在等于0，因此证明元素来自
comes from the right side of the
marquetry
镶嵌，这意味着我们需要将其附加到
which means that we need to append it to
our client hash and then update the hash
我们的客户哈希，然后更新哈希，最后我们检查
and lastly we check that
mirco root that we computed is equal to
我们计算的mirco根等于提供的maca根，因此
the maca root that was provided so
that's how this function works now let's
这就是现在该功能的工作方式，现在让我们在混音中尝试一下
try this function out in remix now
created a separate contract that I'll
创建了一个单独的合同，我将在下面的描述中进行链接
link in the description below
that creates a marquetry from these data
根据这些数据创建镶嵌，并根据此数组计算出的默克尔
and the merkel computed from this array
is this and these are the two issues
是这个，这是我们需要证明的第三个问题
that we need to prove that the third
element is contained in this Merkle tree
元素包含在此Merkle树中，第一个证明元素是
the first proof element is the hash of
the fourth element and the second proof
第四元素和第二证明元素是通过对
element is computed by hashing the
hashes of the first and second element
验证的第一个参数的第一个和第二个元素的哈希
for the first argument of the verify
function we need to pass an array of
函数我们需要传递一个字节数组32我们通过键入
bytes 32 we do that by typing
in a pair of brackets inside the
在方括号内的一对方括号中，我们输入要证明的元素
brackets we enter our to proof elements
notice that we wrap each proof element
请注意，我们将每个证明元素都用双引号引起来，还请注意，
in double quotes also notice that the
order of proof element is important if
如果您改变顺序，那么证明顺序就很重要，那么您
you switch the orders around then you
won't be able to compute the correct
下次我们通过路线时，将无法计算正确的标记或路线
mark or route next we pass in the route
the leaf and the index of the leaf which
叶子和叶子的索引是2
is 2
hit purify and every tongues true so
击中净化，并且所有的舌头都是真实的，所以这证明了这个骇人听闻的
this proves that the macabre was
constructed from an array where the dead
由一个数组构成，其中的死元素等于此数据，并且
element is equal to this data and the
way you can mathematically verify it is
您可以通过采用此哈希和的哈希值来数学验证它的方式
by taking this hash and the hashes of
the proof and if you change any part of
证明，如果您更改输入的任何部分，则验证功能将
the input then the verify function will
return false in this video we went over
在此视频中返回false，我们讨论了镶嵌是默克尔树是
what a marquetry is the Merkel tree is a
tree that is constructed by taking
通过获取配对数据并对配对的哈希进行哈希处理而构成的树
paired data and hashing a pairing the
resulting hashes and then hashing them
产生的散列，然后再次对其进行散列，直到剩下一个散列为止
again until a single hash remains this
is called the Merkel root and it can be
称为默克尔根，可用于加密lipu数据元素
used to cryptographic lipu data element
is contained in array without revealing
包含在数组中而不显示数组中的所有元素之一
all of the elements in the array one
example of this is proving that a
这样的例子证明了一个交易包含在一个区块中
transaction is included in a block
without revealing all of the
没有很好地揭示所有交易，这就是为什么我要
transactions well that's why I got for
this video Merry Christmas Happy New
这个视频圣诞快乐，新年快乐，我会在下一个见
Year's and I'll see you in the next
video
视频